<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nam&#39;s Journal</title>
    <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nam&#39;s Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:02:12 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://namberino.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Phá mã phần mềm điều khiển của jack cắm kết nối WiFi</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/firmware-decryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 12:02:12 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/firmware-decryption/</guid>
      <description>Mình đã học dịch ngược, hệ thống nhúng và phần mềm điều khiển hệ thống nhúng khá lâu rồi. Dạo gần đây mình lại nghĩ &amp;ldquo;Sao mình không kết hợp 2 kĩ năng này để làm 1 cái gì đấy hay?&amp;rdquo;. Thế nên mình thử sức bản thân bằng cách phá mã của 1 phần mềm điều khiển đã được mã hóa của 1 jack cắm kết nối WiFi. Mình đã ghi lại quá trình phá mã và cách suy nghĩ của mình trong bài blog này.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting a Serial-To-WiFi device&#39;s firmware</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/firmware-decryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 14:40:02 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/firmware-decryption/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some research into reverse engineering for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been learning about firmware and embedded systems for a long time. And I thought &amp;ldquo;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be cool to combine these to skills to do something?&amp;rdquo;. So I decided to try decrypting the encrypted firmware of the a Serial-To-WiFi device. I&amp;rsquo;ve documented my process here in this blog post.&#xA;The device I recently read that there was a vulnerability in the Moxa NPort W2150A Serial-To-Wifi device that exploit stack-based buffer overflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fire! But cold</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/cold-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:57:47 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/cold-fire/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across some experiment on youtube about something called &amp;ldquo;cold fire&amp;rdquo;. It sound contradictory, right? How can fire, something that is inherently hot, be cold? Well, that is what we are going to explore in this blog post.&#xA;What is fire? To understand fire, we need to understand plasma. It is the 4th state of matter, right after gas. When a gas gets extremely hot, the electrons inside a substance have enough energy to detach from their atom and move freely.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lửa! Nhưng nó lạnh</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/cold-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:57:47 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/cold-fire/</guid>
      <description>Gần đây mình xem youtube có thấy 1 vài thí nghiệm về 1 thứ gọi là &amp;ldquo;lửa lạnh&amp;rdquo;. Nó nghe rất nghịch lý. Làm thế nào mà lửa, 1 thứ nóng, lại có thể trở nên lạnh được? Đó là điều mình sẽ khám phá trong bài blog này.&#xA;Lửa là gì? Để có thể hiểu được lửa là gì, chúng ta cần hiểu plasma là gì. Plasma là trạng thái vật chất thứ 4, ngay sau khí.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESXiArgs: An Analysis</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/esxiargs-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:42:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/esxiargs-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Last year, a ransomware attack called ESXiArgs managed to encrypt hundreds of VMware machines in multiple different countries. And I decided to try my hands at reverse engineering and analyzing this malware to see how it works. So without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s reverse this.&#xA;Note: The malware sample was provided by the bleepingcomputer forum&#xA;The script So right out of the gate, in the script, there&amp;rsquo;s a section called CHANGE CONFIG:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phân tích mã độc ESXiArgs</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/esxiargs-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:42:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/esxiargs-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Năm vừa qua có xảy ra 1 vụ tấn công ransomware gọi là ESXiArgs. Vũ tấn công này đã làm mã hóa hàng trăm các máy ảo VMware khác nhau. Và mình quyết định là sẽ thử sức dịch ngược và phân tích mã độc này để xem nó hoạt động thế nào.&#xA;Note: Mẫu mã độc này được lấy từ forum bleepingcomputer&#xA;Script chạy Mình sẽ bắt đầu bằng phân tích script chạy mã đọc trước:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8-bit Computer in FPGA</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/8bit-computer-fpga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 10:01:26 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/8bit-computer-fpga/</guid>
      <description>Computers are mysterious. These machines have always been so enigmatic to most people. I can guarantee that if you ask someone on the road how computers work, they would most likely just answer &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;I was like that for a long time, even after I started learning programming. So I decided that I will learn how a computer works by building one.&#xA;At first, I was thinking about building a breadboard computer like Ben Eater.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dự án máy tính 8-bit trên FPGA</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/8bit-computer-fpga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 10:01:26 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/8bit-computer-fpga/</guid>
      <description>Máy tính là 1 công cụ khá là thần bí với đa số mọi người. Mình đảm bảo là nếu như mình hỏi random 1 người trên đường về cách máy tính hoạt động kiểu gì thì có khả năng rất cao là họ sẽ trả lời là &amp;ldquo;Tôi không biết&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Mình cũng từng là 1 người như thế, mình có ý tưởng mơ hồ về cách máy tính hoạt động: lập trình code, dịch code xuống mã nhị phân, máy tính đọc mã nhị phân rồi chạy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware vô hại nhất trên thế giới</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/harmless-ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 17:37:37 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/vietnamese/posts/harmless-ransomware/</guid>
      <description>Lưu ý: Không sử dụng phần mềm này cho việc xấu. Phần mềm này được làm cho mục đích học tập. Nếu bạn muốn chạy ransomware này thì chạy nó trong môi trường ảo, môi trường đã được cách ly. Đừng sử dụng nó cho việc xấu!&#xA;Kể từ khi mình bắt đầu xem phim Mr. Robot, mình thấy rất hứng thú với hacker và hack. Mình không phải là hacker nhưng mình rất thích học về các cách hack mà nhiều người khác nghĩ ra.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world&#39;s most harmless ransomware</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/harmless-ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 17:37:37 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/en/english/posts/harmless-ransomware/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Please do NOT use this for malicious intent. This is purely for educational purpose only. If you do want to run this ransomware, run it in an isolated environment. STAY SAFE AND DON&amp;rsquo;T GET IN TROUBLE!&#xA;Ever since I started watching Mr. Robot, I got really interested in hacking and hackers. I&amp;rsquo;m not a hacker myself but I do like learning about how people have found ways to exploit computers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
