<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nam&#39;s Journal</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nam&#39;s Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 22:37:58 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make an HTTP server with Assembly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/lets-make-an-http-server-with-assembly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 22:37:58 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025/01/lets-make-an-http-server-with-assembly/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make an Operating System: The boot sector [Part 1]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/lets-make-an-operating-system-the-boot-sector-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 14:20:39 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/lets-make-an-operating-system-the-boot-sector-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/lets-make-an-operating-system-the-beginning/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, we finished installing and setting up our tools for developing an operating system. This post will start the development of our OS&amp;rsquo;s boot sector.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-bios&#34;&gt;The BIOS&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;BIOS&lt;/em&gt; is a program that the computer uses to start the computer system after it is powered on. It is the program responsible for loading and setting up the hardware and system in a computer and loading up the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling a Thrust Vector Control Rocket in Python</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/modeling-a-thrust-vector-control-rocket-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 20:31:39 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/modeling-a-thrust-vector-control-rocket-in-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rocketry has always been a fascinating topic for me and I&amp;rsquo;d love to get into model rocketry because it seems so interesting. Unfortunately, due to where I live, I can&amp;rsquo;t really get into it due to lack of materials, cost, and local laws. So what&amp;rsquo;s a guy to do when he wants to get into rocketry but can&amp;rsquo;t physically do it? He goes the virtual simulation route.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be building a simulation for a simple thrust vector control (&lt;strong&gt;TVC&lt;/strong&gt;) rocket. This rocket will be modeled pretty accurately to life, it won&amp;rsquo;t be 100% realistic since it&amp;rsquo;s just a simulation, but it will be mostly correct. I&amp;rsquo;ll be documenting everything from start to finish so that anyone who wants to can follow along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make an Operating System: The beginning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/lets-make-an-operating-system-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:12:15 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/06/lets-make-an-operating-system-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to build an operating system from &lt;strong&gt;scratch&lt;/strong&gt;. Why you may ask? Well, I had finished an operating system class a few semester ago but it was a whole lot of theory and no practice on those theory what so ever. After that class, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I truly understand operating system and how they work. So I decided to try to make my own operating system to get more practical experience and a deeper understanding of OS development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting a Serial-To-WiFi device&#39;s firmware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/decrypting-a-serial-to-wifi-devices-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 14:40:02 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/decrypting-a-serial-to-wifi-devices-firmware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some research into reverse engineering for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been learning about firmware and embedded systems for a long time. And I thought &amp;ldquo;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be cool to combine these to skills to do something?&amp;rdquo;. So I decided to try decrypting the encrypted firmware of the a Serial-To-WiFi device. I&amp;rsquo;ve documented my process here in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-device&#34;&gt;The device&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently read that there was a vulnerability in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.moxa.com/en/products/industrial-edge-connectivity/serial-device-servers/wireless-device-servers/nport-w2150a-w2250a-series&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moxa NPort W2150A Serial-To-Wifi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; device that exploit stack-based buffer overflow. I decided I would take a shot at decrypting the firmware for this device, which was encrypted by default.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fire! But cold</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/fire-but-cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:57:47 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/fire-but-cold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across some experiment on youtube about something called &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;cold fire&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. It sound contradictory, right? How can fire, something that is inherently hot, be cold? Well, that is what we are going to explore in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-fire&#34;&gt;What is fire?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand fire, we need to understand &lt;strong&gt;plasma&lt;/strong&gt;. It is the 4th state of matter, right after gas. When a gas gets extremely hot, the electrons inside a substance have enough energy to detach from their atom and move freely. This makes the atoms become highly charged due to the lack of electrons and they form a collection of charged particles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESXiArgs: An Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/esxiargs-an-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 14:42:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/04/esxiargs-an-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year, a ransomware attack called &lt;strong&gt;ESXiArgs&lt;/strong&gt; managed to encrypt hundreds of VMware machines in multiple different countries. And I decided to try my hands at reverse engineering and analyzing this malware to see how it works. So without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s reverse this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: The malware sample was provided by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/forums/t/782193/esxi-ransomware-help-and-support-topic-esxiargs-args-extension/page-14#entry5470686&#34;&gt;bleepingcomputer forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-script&#34;&gt;The script&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So right out of the gate, in the script, there&amp;rsquo;s a section called &lt;code&gt;CHANGE CONFIG&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8-bit Computer in FPGA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/02/8-bit-computer-in-fpga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 10:01:26 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/02/8-bit-computer-in-fpga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computers are mysterious. These machines have always been so enigmatic to most people. I can guarantee that if you ask someone on the road how computers work, they would most likely just answer &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was like that for a long time, even after I started learning programming. So I decided that I will learn how a computer works by building one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At first, I was thinking about building a breadboard computer like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLowKtXNTBypGqImE405J2565dvjafglHU&#34;&gt;Ben Eater&lt;/a&gt;. But then I realized that I don&amp;rsquo;t really have access to a lot of the components that Ben used where I live so I decided to make this computer using software, and since I just started learning &lt;strong&gt;Verilog&lt;/strong&gt;, I decided to put my &lt;strong&gt;Verilog&lt;/strong&gt; skill to the test by making this computer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world&#39;s most harmless ransomware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/02/the-worlds-most-harmless-ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 17:37:37 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/02/the-worlds-most-harmless-ransomware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: Please do &lt;strong&gt;NOT&lt;/strong&gt; use this for malicious intent. This is purely for educational purpose only. If you do want to run this ransomware, run it in an isolated environment. &lt;strong&gt;STAY SAFE AND DON&amp;rsquo;T GET IN TROUBLE!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started watching &lt;em&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/em&gt;, I got really interested in hacking and hackers. I&amp;rsquo;m not a hacker myself but I do like learning about how people have found ways to exploit computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pressure of OceanGate&#39;s Titan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/02/the-pressure-of-oceangates-titan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 12:27:06 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/02/the-pressure-of-oceangates-titan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was bored so I went down the rabbit hole of engineering disasters. One disaster that caught my eyes was the &lt;em&gt;OceanGate&amp;rsquo;s Titan incident&lt;/em&gt;. It caught my eyes because I was curious about how much pressure was applied onto the submarine at that depth, so I grab my calculator and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most dangerous thing about deep ocean is probably the hydrostatic pressure. This pressure is proportional to the depth measured from the surface of the water body. The weight of the body of fluid gradually increases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
