<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Physics on Nam&#39;s Journal</title>
    <link>https://namberino.github.io/tags/physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Physics on Nam&#39;s Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:57:47 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://namberino.github.io/tags/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fire! But cold</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/04/fire-but-cold/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:57:47 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/04/fire-but-cold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across some experiment on youtube about something called &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;cold fire&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. It sound contradictory, right? How can fire, something that is inherently hot, be cold? Well, that is what we are going to explore in this blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-fire&#34;&gt;What is fire?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand fire, we need to understand &lt;strong&gt;plasma&lt;/strong&gt;. It is the 4th state of matter, right after gas. When a gas gets extremely hot, the electrons inside a substance have enough energy to detach from their atom and move freely. This makes the atoms become highly charged due to the lack of electrons and they form a collection of charged particles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The pressure of OceanGate&#39;s Titan</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/02/the-pressure-of-oceangates-titan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 12:27:06 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/02/the-pressure-of-oceangates-titan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was bored so I went down the rabbit hole of engineering disasters. One disaster that caught my eyes was the &lt;em&gt;OceanGate&amp;rsquo;s Titan incident&lt;/em&gt;. It caught my eyes because I was curious about how much pressure was applied onto the submarine at that depth, so I grab my calculator and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most dangerous thing about deep ocean is probably the hydrostatic pressure. This pressure is proportional to the depth measured from the surface of the water body. The weight of the body of fluid gradually increases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
