<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Nam&#39;s Journal</title>
    <link>https://namberino.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Nam&#39;s Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:12:15 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://namberino.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s make an Operating System [Part 1]</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/06/lets-make-an-operating-system-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 22:12:15 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/06/lets-make-an-operating-system-part-1/</guid>
      <description>We are going to build an operating system from scratch. Why you may ask? Well, I had finished an operating system class a few semester ago but it was a whole lot of theory and no practice on those theory what so ever. After that class, I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I truly understand operating system and how they work. So I decided to try to make my own operating system to get more practical experience and a deeper understanding of OS development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting a Serial-To-WiFi device&#39;s firmware</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/04/decrypting-a-serial-to-wifi-devices-firmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 14:40:02 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/04/decrypting-a-serial-to-wifi-devices-firmware/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some research into reverse engineering for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been learning about firmware and embedded systems for a long time. And I thought &amp;ldquo;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be cool to combine these to skills to do something?&amp;rdquo;. So I decided to try decrypting the encrypted firmware of the a Serial-To-WiFi device. I&amp;rsquo;ve documented my process here in this blog post.&#xA;The device I recently read that there was a vulnerability in the Moxa NPort W2150A Serial-To-Wifi device that exploit stack-based buffer overflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8-bit Computer in FPGA</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/02/8-bit-computer-in-fpga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 10:01:26 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/02/8-bit-computer-in-fpga/</guid>
      <description>Computers are mysterious. These machines have always been so enigmatic to most people. I can guarantee that if you ask someone on the road how computers work, they would most likely just answer &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;I was like that for a long time, even after I started learning programming. So I decided that I will learn how a computer works by building one.&#xA;At first, I was thinking about building a breadboard computer like Ben Eater.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The world&#39;s most harmless ransomware</title>
      <link>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/02/the-worlds-most-harmless-ransomware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 17:37:37 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://namberino.github.io/posts/2024/02/the-worlds-most-harmless-ransomware/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Please do NOT use this for malicious intent. This is purely for educational purpose only. If you do want to run this ransomware, run it in an isolated environment. STAY SAFE AND DON&amp;rsquo;T GET IN TROUBLE!&#xA;Ever since I started watching Mr. Robot, I got really interested in hacking and hackers. I&amp;rsquo;m not a hacker myself but I do like learning about how people have found ways to exploit computers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
